# **Howard Lynch**

Phone: +353 862185243

Email: howielynch@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile https://ie.linkedin.com/in/howie-lynch-1a7a90115

GitHub Profile <a href="https://github.com/Thegrinch1985">https://github.com/Thegrinch1985</a>

Online Portfolio <a href="https://thegrinch1985.github.io/Howard\_Lynch\_Portfolio">https://thegrinch1985.github.io/Howard\_Lynch\_Portfolio</a>

### **SUMMARY**

I am currently entering my final year of a 4-year Computer Science Degree at the Institute of Technology Tallaght, Dublin. My goal, upon completion of my course, is to further my career in the IT industry while constantly learning and improving my already capable skill set. As of the start of September I will begin the last year of my course. I am aiming for a result of a 1.1 distinction Honours Degree and am confident in my ability to achieving this. I feel that during this time, in both ITT and at VHI, I have gained the extensive technical, theoretical and practical experience required for a graduate job on completion of my degree in June 2019. I can learn quickly and also enjoying teaching what I know to others. I am a fantastic team player with excellent interpersonal and IT based skills. I can also produce the necessary results required when on a deadline, as I have done at VHI. I feel I can be an excellent addition to any team, especially one requiring an ambitious and motivated character. Support given to me will be reciprocated in the form of hard work and dedication to the task(s) at hand.

### **IT SKILLS**

- Proficient user of Java, C++
- SQL gueries to intermediate level using Oracle 11G
- Design and create database schemas
- Designing and developing websites using JavaScript, CSS, HTML, and Bootstrap
- Competent user of Windows and Linux Operating Systems.
- Competent user of Linux Terminal
- Capable of resolving hardware and software-based issues
- Capable of building and troubleshooting networks using routers
- Configure a router using the Cisco IOS command set
- Automation, Writing Scripts in UFT and also selenium
- Experience of using version control systems GIT and SVN
- Understanding of software designs patterns and the principles object orientated design
- Logical, Analytical and creative approach to problems

### **EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS**

### 2015 - to-date BSc Computing

Institute of Technology Tallaght, Dublin 24

Current G.P.A: 3.02 (3rd year), 3.38 (2nd year) 1st year (3.42)

### 3<sup>rd</sup> Year Modules studied,

Data Structures & Algorithms(B+), Operating Systems (B+), Advanced Databases(B), Cloud and distribution(C+), Web Application Development (C+), Data Analysis(C+)

**2**<sup>nd</sup> **Year Modules studied**, Discrete Maths2 **(A)**; Networking2 **(A)**; Software Development 4 **(A)**; Software Development 3 **(A)**; Networking1 **(B+)**; Operating Systems**(B+)**; Databases **(B+)**; Management Science**(B+)**; Web Design & Development1 **(B)**; Object Orientated Design & Analysis **(B)**; Info Security **(B)**;

1st Year Modules studied, Software Development (A); Discrete Mathematics (A); Software Development 2 (A); Statistics (A); Web and Database Fundamentals (B+); Computer Architecture (B); Business & Information Systems (B); Systems Analysis (B); Communications (B); Introduction to Operating Systems (B); Systems Analysis 2 (B);

### Significant Projects Undertaken

Currently Working with IBM for industry based final year project.

### Online Shopping Site with Administrative and Customer Access

### Description

A team project that involved the creation of a dynamic web site which allowed the user to buy multiple products. It also allowed an Administrator to add, update edit and delete products. This was done inside the Java play framework and incorporated several languages including Java, HTML, JavaScript, SQL. Creating it from scratch was a challenge but helped me gain a much better understanding of how dynamic websites work.

# **Challenges faced:**

- Finding a solution that insured that only the Administrator Could Add, Delete or Edit products
- Insuring that if a product was bought that it would decrement inside the database and if out of stock would inform the User

### **Technologies & Tools Used:**

Java, HTML, JavaScript, SQL, Java Play Framework

#### Work Placement:

**January 2018 – September 2018** VHI Healthcare Abbey Street / Custom House Plaza

I began a work placement in February with VHI and it has been a fantastic experience for me. It has improved my understanding of the inner workings of IT, as used in the business world, whilst also understanding the necessary requirements for building and structuring IT projects, both alone and in a team. My work in the Automation team consisted of writing scripts and test cases in both UFT and Selenium. In the Web-Development team I was introduced to software I hadn't used before, such as Gradle and Web-logic, both of which I am now proficient in. I gained much knowledge while at VHI after being shown many new technologies and software such as those mentioned above

## **Qualifications & Education Record**

2014 – 2015	Computer Science FETAC level	Blackrock College of Further
		Education (BFEI)

1997 – 2003 Leaving Certificate 2003 St. Davids

**Employment History** 

September 2001 – 03 Cheers Off –License Delgany, Co. Wicklow

June 2004 – 2011 Painter and Decorator Greystones / Australia

### **Online Courses**

Currently enrolled in:

### Udemy -

- The Complete Java Developer Course, learn Step by Step by Tim Buchalka. I am using this course to help me along with my college studies very helpful and informative.
- Oracle SQL, Step by Step by Amaranth Reddy, Oracle.
   Using this also as extra college material very useful resources.

### Harvard CS50

CS50: Introduction to Computer Science
 An extra course I have enrolled in and when I have time, I try to continue with my progress.
 Very different to what I am learning in college as it practices Language I have not studied yet,
 Python being the main Language.

#### **REFERENCES**

Jimmy Bryden Technical Project Manager VHI Group Services DAC

Jimmy.bryden@vhi.ie

0868591885

Frank Sullivan It Solutions Head of Automation 0858514818 Frank.sullivan@sqs.com